<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Gonzalo García-Castro</title>
    <link>http://gongcastro.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Gonzalo García-Castro</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://gongcastro.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>@psicotuiterbot: Un bot de Twitter para Psicotuiter</title>
      <link>http://gongcastro.github.io/2021/12/29/psicotuiterbot-un-bot-de-twitter-para-psicotuiter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gongcastro.github.io/2021/12/29/psicotuiterbot-un-bot-de-twitter-para-psicotuiter/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR: He creado un bot de Twitter que hace RT a cualquier mención a #psicotuiter. El código está escrito en R usando el paquete {rtweet} para interactuar con la API de Twitter, y está alojado en una Raspberry Pi que ejecuta el código cada 15 usando CRON, haciendo las veces de servidor.
Follow @psicotuiterbotEste es el timeline de [@psicotuiterbot](https://twitter.com/psicotuiterbot):
Tweets by psicotuiterbotLa comunidad de PsicotuiterPsicotuiter (aka.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creando un paquete de R: una guía informal (I)</title>
      <link>http://gongcastro.github.io/2021/11/14/creando-un-paquete-de-r-una-guia-informal-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gongcastro.github.io/2021/11/14/creando-un-paquete-de-r-una-guia-informal-i/</guid>
      <description>En este tutorial en colaboración con Alicia Franco-Martínez @AliciaFrancoXVE1, explicaremos cómo se ha creado el paquete de R {psicotuiteR}. En el canal de Twitch de Alicia, Psicometries (al que también debéis suscribiros), hicimos un directo en el que intentamos mostrar por encima lo que trataré en este tutorial. Trataremos de explicar cada paso lo mejor que podamos para que puedas replicarlo, contribuir al mismo paquete o incluso crear tu propio paquete en el futuro.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualising polynomial regression</title>
      <link>http://gongcastro.github.io/2021/01/21/visualising-polynomial-regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gongcastro.github.io/2021/01/21/visualising-polynomial-regression/</guid>
      <description>TL;DRThe outputs of polynomial regression can be difficult to interpret. I generated some animated plots to see how model predictions change across different combinations of coefficients for 1st, 2nd, and 3rd degree polynomials.
Why polynomialsWhen modelling data using regression, sometimes the relationship between input variables and output variables is not very well captured by a straight line. A standard linear model is defined by the equation</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How similar is the word &#34;mask&#34; across languages?</title>
      <link>http://gongcastro.github.io/2020/11/20/how-similar-is-the-word-mask-across-languages/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gongcastro.github.io/2020/11/20/how-similar-is-the-word-mask-across-languages/</guid>
      <description>The ubiquity of masks has given psycholinguists a frequent-ish stimulus to use in experiments. This word is more form-similar across languages than one may think. I gathered a big-ish dataset with translation equivalents of the word mask across ~110 languages. I tweeted about this today, and wanted to dedicate some more lines to nuance.
The ubiquity of #masks😷 has given psycholinguists a frequent-ish stimulus to use in experiments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Importing data from multiple files simultaneously in R</title>
      <link>http://gongcastro.github.io/2020/07/05/importing-data-from-multiple-files-simultaneously-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gongcastro.github.io/2020/07/05/importing-data-from-multiple-files-simultaneously-in-r/</guid>
      <description>TL;DRWe need to import several CSV or TXT files and merge them into one data frame in R. Regardless of what function we use to import the files, vectorising the operation using purrr::map in combination with do.call or dplyr::bind_rows is the most time-efficient method (~25 ms importing 50 files with 10,000 rows each), compared to for loops (~220ms) or using lapply (~123 ms). data.table::fread is the fastest function for importing data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A primer on Mixed-Effects Models: Theory and practice</title>
      <link>http://gongcastro.github.io/2020/03/31/a-primer-on-mixed-effects-models-theory-and-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gongcastro.github.io/2020/03/31/a-primer-on-mixed-effects-models-theory-and-practice/</guid>
      <description>When I started my PhD I had to get familiar with Linear Mixed Models very well very quickly. Then I was asked to present what I learnt and prepare this informal tutorial for my colleagues, which I presented on March 10th, 2020 (yes, early pandemic 😖). This post shares the result.
This is not supposed to be taken as a formal guide to linear mixed-effects models, but rather as a semi-coherent compilation of notes and self-suggestions that I considered worth sharing with my lab mates during my early stages of in the PhD.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
